Oh, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 99, we are going to demonstrate that hash table usage
in Java and how we can add the remove and bring the hash table and so on.
So let's make a class that works with the hash table and see how we can add the elements inside that
create a Java class called hash table.
By the way, you can download all of these source codes from the Resources folder and under every exercise
our Udemy course.
So I will start by public static void, main stream args.
OK.
Since we don't need to go deeply into hash tables and they are not asked, not frequently asked in universities
or interviews.
So we are going to implement the hash table from the Java package.
So this is the hash table.
The hash table.
Hash table starting Java, you.
So we have imported the Java that you feel the hash table, that code, and we will.
It is not.
No need to mention that generic Typekit was.
So I would put here that the first one integer and the second one is the string.
So we are making a map or in a hash table that correspondent for the key as integer.
And the value is the three you give me, the integer I will give to the string hash table it up to the
new hash table.
So initialization of the hash table using genetics could be equal to the same thing.
Can make the same hash table, but we can make.
Reinserting integer and the string I gave here.
OK, so
I will make insert elements using put method inserting elements into hash paper.
We use Hash Table Dot.
We have many methods.
Clear size clue and computer and so on.
We need to use the method put.
Here is the point we get that integer key and the string value.
So we are going to insert the key and that values one.
I will name it as Ali.
Hash table put to Mohammad
hash table that put the
Night Alice hash table to put four and we passed the string value here would be passed as like.
Charge.
OK.
This is how we insert the elements into hash tape.
OK, so let's print, print and print here.
System that brings them mapping, we are doing things the map
not being of hash table, we put plus hash table, let's run and see.
I'm stable
and you see, guys, they're mapping mappings of hash table for equal to George, three equal to Alice
do is equal to Muhammad and one is equal to Ali.
No.
Let's see there another methods of war for working with the hashtag.
That's a check.
If a key is present and present in the venue,
pretend that Earth hash table contains key or contains values, you can check for the key or you can
check for the value.
OK, I'm going to check number five.
It's not presented, but let me check if it's contains the key.
Then.
Integer,
or we can make this string can make it like this system that out that print and because the value
equal to the hash table
don't get.
Object at key.
That's Iran and see.
It will not print anything because it is not containing power five.
No, let's check for the four four three.
OK, we get that value.
We need to start it into an integer at first.
So here I will create integer a equals hash table dot get five or three.
Then we print an object.
Then we print a.
Let's turn on Nancy.
And here we go with pass number three is three corresponding to our list, so I pass the key.
I will get the value as A..
Now let's try to remove elements from the hash table.
So here,
removing
elements, hash table, the community move and we passed the index that we are going to remove.
So this is the key that we are going to remove if we print the hash table again
after putting thing.
We Iran, we get like this.
This is their mapping, this is the voluntary search, and after removing, we have removed the index
for George.
So we get three Alice do Muhammad and Mohammad.
Now let's learn about the hash table interface is extending from the map.
So if we need to iterating using enhanced or loop, we start by four map thought and three of.
Integer, pretty strange for every element to make an element such as good at hash table thought and
to set this entry set method.
If we see it to a return, a set of entry of integer and string.
So we will use this method in order to store it inside.
And every time every element inside this hash table make a map for it in a way in order to allow us
to print system to print every element of this and we get the key, get the key glass space and we get
it to get that OK.
This is how we relate to using the enhanced four new let's run and see the result.
Here we have three lists to Mohammad and one as I see guys how we can iterate through the values and
the keys of.
Of the hash table using the map, and it's very simple, a very, very, very frequently asked questions
like how to iterate using the enhanced two and side.